Every week I pick some small businesses at
random and give them critiques on how
they can improve their social media
and maybe their sales process.
If you would like to apply, there
is a link in the description below,
and it could
be you in the next video.
We're going to begin with Sushi Yogi.
And I don't do any preemptive research on
these. I just jump right in.
I play what's in front of me.
Private Ashtanga yoga teacher.
Let's check out the content.
Taught 4,140 private sessions and
in these classes-
So there's no hook here. So to begin with,
straight away, I like the fact
that you've probably just got a camera set
up in class.
You're doing the hard bit, which
is the lesson,
and there's an edit going on in the
background.
But if you're going to pay someone
or go to the extent of having this
editing go on in the background,
why couldn't there have been a hook?
Because what I realized is now imagine,
guys, your mind is so-
Music's too loud.
So many creators think
that music can add this
emotional effect to their content.
If your music is a little bit too quiet,
fine.
If it's too loud, I'm gone.
If you're feeling pulled in a thousand
different directions by wellness trends
that
ask you to wake up at 5:00-
Again, I'll probably say
that music's a little bit too loud.
If you're someone in this niche that's
already doing quite well, I would implore
you to potentially look at some other
people.
You should 100% check out Liv in Leggings.
Down dog.
Your heels do not need to touch the mat.
Some-
Statement hook, in downward dog,
your heels do not need to touch the mat.
26,000 likes.
Did you know you can stretch all of the
major muscles in your body in just
three stretch-
I could argue that maybe the music's a
little bit too loud on this one, but maybe
this is just a yoga trend. Question hook.
If you're short on time.
Now, the one trend
that I think we can say we can take from
someone like Liv is
that every single piece of her content
is designed, boom, to you
as a person. So I feel like
if you're going to set up a third-party
camera
shot in a studio, go to all this effort,
maybe that mat should've been brought a
bit closer,
and you should have addressed a problem to
the very person that you're
talking to.
As far as an ideation standpoint, 100%,
every time you
get to the end of a yoga class,
think to yourself, what
was a struggle that someone
went through? What was an insecurity
that someone had?
What was a position they found difficult?
What cues were you using to help those
people? Class finishes.
Rather than trying to record it in class,
take the mat over to the camera.
If you're someone
that loses your balance in warrior three,
here are three cues you
can, et cetera.
Just feel like we're missing maybe a
little bit here of that
connection with the audience. Now,
when you're talking to the camera here,
it's
very difficult for me to know
that you're a yoga instructor.
Think of it like this candle flame.
Beautiful.
So as soon as you start talking,
I'm someone that's just swiping along on
socials,
I'm gone.
So I would like a combination of you
talking to me and addressing my
problems mixed in with the yoga.
Let's have a look for an outlier
that you've
potentially had. Not many.
Float into position, finding-
Let's open with a problem every time.
I guarantee if I was to say to you,
what are 10 things
that people struggle with in
yoga, you could reel things off, ba, ba,
ba, ba, bam. We're just not getting that.
And in the nicest way possible,
I would argue that all of these approaches
that
you're using are not breaking mainstream
enough.
People's problems, work backwards.
Over the next 100 posts,
I want you to solve 100 problems
that people in yoga
suffer with.
I like the name Sushi Yoga as well.
Very good.
Now, just before we get to your website,
don't seem to see you on
YouTube. And again, the reason I say this,
Liv in Leggings crushes on here.
620,000 subscribers. Some of her videos,
mad
amounts of engagement. And again,
you could go there.
You could take inspiration from these
and put them into your short-term content.
Now, when I get to your website,
virtual offering, Yoga Mastery Program.
Again,
I'm not a big fan of text over images
or over videos.
It makes it very difficult to read.
I like this appeal to authority with the
seen on, et cetera.
Now,
this bit I did have a quick look at
beforehand.
Hello. Hi there.
There seems to be like background noise.
It's almost like someone's eating a packet
of crisps.
What's your name? My name is Sushmita.
Hello, Sushmita.
From an ASMR standpoint, terrible.
No offense.
No,
maybe you do need a little bit of offense.
Now, this is a VSL.
It's a video sales letter.
It's 19 minutes long.
I just want to sit you down,
get a camera in front of you, and go,
"What could I
get out of joining your yoga program
and how could it benefit me?
Why should I give you 10 pounds a month
or whatever it is?" And for you to just
answer that for me. Again,
this very small copy, hard to
read, lot of dead space. I get down here.
I don't really know what
is the main thing of this.
Private sessions, group classes,
online courses.
Surely this is going to be very different
offerings.
Private sessions are going to be for
people that probably live near you,
which I
don't know where it is. Group classes,
wouldn't that probably be tied into that?
And online courses,
as in I'm going to become yoga qualified?
Am I a yoga enthusiast or am I? It's just
very difficult to figure this out.
Shala within, consult, private sessions.
I'm probably going to bounce.
Then down here, a load of videos.
I want you to treat me like I'm an idiot.
And when I land on your page,
I want this to be such an easy process
where I come down and I know what it is.
Discovery call. One-to-one consult.
I didn't even know you
were in South Africa.
I would love to see something more centric
around solving people's problems.
And second of all,
I would like a landing page that just
is a little bit less
chaotic. Namaste. Next person here we got.
I'm not even going to try to pronounce
your name. King Voytek. Are you a king?
If not, why'd you call yourself a king?
Straight up.
Second of all,
for this to be your profile picture,
it looks like it was taken on
an iPhone 11 pre-pandemic with 32 thumb
marks smudged
on the bloody lens. This
is not a good image for representative of
the
business. Now here,
I help men make real progress.
How old are you, bro?
That's my first question. How old are you?
Because this manosphere,
dudes helping dudes.
Let's have a look.
I don't even know what this is about.
[upbeat music]
A year in the life of 30 seconds. One,
no one cares.
Two, chessboard.
I just feel like you've watched too much
Andrew Tate stuff, and
you put in a hashtag there for
self-improvement.
Hashtags don't do anything, bro.
They don't.
Even the CEO of Instagram has said it over
and over again.
That doesn't do anything.
Life could be great
if you just show up for yourself.
Where do I send the money?
Block with a white front door in the
corner subtle-
When you love what you do, you do more.
Is this supposed to be like a motivational
quote page?
You're not going to be able to just
plaster quotes from the passenger seat of
your
mate's car and expect people to want to do
business with you.
Again,
every business revolves around
problem-solving. What is going on here?
Life when you take progress seriously.
What is that?
Wearing a gilet in a car using your phone
whilst driving. Oh, wow.
How can I be you, bro? This is,
I don't get it, bro.
Then you've got lessons.
Lessons of King Voytek.
Why'd you call yourself a king in the
first place?
Matter of fact, you've got 22 posts,
300 followers. Who made you a king?
Lessons of King Voytek. What is this,
bruv?
Then what is this Shot here on holiday.
Oh, mate, yeah.
Can you get this pic?
I'm just going to sit on the edge of the
pool and look away.
You ready? Yeah.
How did that pic look? Take another pic.
Did you get it? Self-improvement,
achieve clarity, walk away with
confidence.
You've not solved any of my problems to do
with any of these things.
If you can transform like this,
you can step by step... Bro,
you just grew up.
You went through puberty,
and you're trying to sell it.
Are you lazy? It's a simple yes
or no answer,
and before you do anything about it,
you need to ask yourself that question,
and you better be fucking honest about it.
Your problem is your mind is cluttered,
and you're in the wrong environment.
You tolerate low standards-
Are you fed up? Take a walk. Mate,
this just isn't good enough.
And why would you put this on this page,
but not on the main page?
Why are you running two profiles here?
Let's check out your website.
So first of all,
you're asking for my email address.
So is this a squeeze page, or
is this a landing page? Look at this,
mate.
You got three products which
are in reverse order,
which doesn't make any sense.
We read left to right,
so it should start with 0, 22, 99.
Also, if you have a $0 product,
this should be its own page, which
is just the
whole point of it is to get email
addresses.
To put it next to paid products makes no
sense. There's no video sales letter.
You're not even telling me what it
is in your socials.
No one's going to come here, bro,
to a fucking 20-year-old
that calls himself a
king. The Young Men's Blueprint,
a complete self-development course
designed specifically for guys ready to
stop drifting and start building.
What have you done? Mate, I'm not a fan,
mate, if I'm perfectly honest.
This needs a lot of work.
Think of it this way,
if you want your online business to
do well,
you probably need a lot of people to be
complimenting you on your content.
So imagine this.
For my online mentorship to do well,
I know that I need for random
people to start saying, "Mate,
really enjoying your business content."
If people in
my network of friends or even people
that I train jujitsu with aren't going,
"Mate,
your business channel's really helping
me," and they're not giving me any money,
I
know I'm on the right track. But
if it doesn't do that,
it's just not good enough.
There was absolutely nothing of value on
your page.
So,
if I don't get anything of value from you
for free, why the hell would I feel
compelled to buy stuff?
The next application here,
No Stress Social.
I like the handle.
I like the clean branding here.
"I make things easier for small
businesses." Oh,
now I'm interested. Okay.
"I get you set up, seen,
and selling." Ooh,
I like that. Facebook, Instagram, TikTok.
"Register your interest below." All right,
let's see your socials first. Calm down.
Put your dick away. Where's the sound?
No sound.
All right, so your two videos there,
no sound. What about here?
No Stress Social.
"Your business deserves to be seen.
Make it happen." Again,
hashtags quite literally don't do
anything.
Okay, cool.
We got our first post of value. Let's go.
"Five ways to make social media
stress-free." "Batch your content." Cool.
Okay. I don't like batching my content,
but okay. "Reuse and repurpose.
Stop creating from scratch.
Repurpose old content." Okay.
"Keep it simple.
Done is better than perfect." Okay.
"Engagement over followers." It's 10 weeks
old, mate. You got 22 likes on this.
"Which tip do you need most?
Comment below." You got a bot. That
was it.
How do you make things easier for small
businesses when you can't even make things
easy for yourself? One like, no sound.
"Perfection is the biggest lie holding you
back from your progress.
If you're tired of feeling stuck,
I'd love to help you simplify your social
media.
DM me 'start.'" You don't even put sound
on your flipping videos.
No one's DMing you.
I'm not getting helped with this content.
Let's try this.
"Five daily habits to grow on Instagram."
This is supposed to be No Stress Social.
I'm stressed for you because your content
is dog shit.
"DM me 'habits.' Start by replying to
anyone who's engaged," which
in your case is no one because your
content is poo.
"One helpful tip,
a behind-the-scenes reminder." Poo.
"Like, comment,
or respond to stories." Poo.
"Don't wait until you're feeling
overwhelmed by content creation." No
offense,
your content is rubbish.
No one's going to connect with this stuff.
"Is this you?" Here we go. "If I
was starting from zero followers,
I'd do this."
How are you an authority in this?
You're not getting comments.
You're not getting anyone resonating with
your content because I feel like I'm
talking to a bot. If you told me this
was a page run by ChatGPT.
You're talking about having a content
plan, but you have not got a content plan.
Look, mate,
and stop turning yourself into a cartoon
on ChatGPT.
If you're going to help people grow on
social media,
you should be at least able to
grow on social media.
If you want to be a personal trainer,
you need to have your
own house in order.
You don't have to have a six-pack,
but you need to be competent
in some realm of sport or fitness.
If you can't even turn up for your
own business,
how can I expect you to turn up for mine?
"Register your interest below." I can't
even access your Google Form, mate.
This is so dog shit.
You say you're making things easier for
small
businesses. You are a small business,
and you can't do anything right.
You couldn't even get your link in your
bio right, mate.
This is anything but low-stress social.
This is bollocks, mate.
It really is.
Why don't you just get out your fucking
phone, sit down at home,
and actually give me some tangible bits of
information that I can run with?
Put it this way, in your next 100 videos,
just press record, help me with
some part of social media, chop it up,
put captions on it, put it out.
If in the next 100 posts,
you don't start seeing an uptake in
engagement, go do
another job for a living, mate,
because yeah, this is just terrible.
And look,
you're following people just in the hope
that they follow you back.
There's no marketing here.
Your top of funnel here is awful, and
there's no strategy. Sorry, but it's bad.
It's really bad. No Stress Social,
just call it No Social because you got no
social
presence.
Moving on to Aaron Burgess Fitness.
Women's weight loss coach.
You're missing one of them little
apostrophes there because the weight loss
coach
should belong to the women if you
are the women's weight loss coach,
just saying.
Now, these pictures, typically,
when it comes to weight loss,
that fat loss
niche, and especially women,
they find bodybuilding quite intimidating.
Now, they might absolutely love this,
but the majority of fat loss
clients see someone
that would put on skimpy undies and
diet for 20 weeks
and cover themselves in fake tan as the
complete
opposite of what they want in someone to
help them lose fat. Just saying.
Straight from the off. So I'd love
that profile picture to change.
Love to get a little apostrophe in there.
15K followers, big man ting.
"I help women lose 20 to 40 pounds in six
months." All right.
"Build your dream body without fad diets.
DM 180 for one-to-one coaching.
Apply to work with me." Hold on.
Am I DMing you,
or am I applying to apply to work
with you?
I don't like the apply to work with bit,
mate.
I would much rather apply free Facebook
group, free resources,
apply for one-to-one.
It's like applying for a Soho House
membership.
It's like applying for something.
I'd love to just know your pricing,
what you offer. I can't even get that.
Now,
these reels don't be seeming to get much
traction.
Here are my top five fat loss hacks
that most women aren't doing enough of-
Something a bit up with this audio here
... but should do every day. And yes,
I am a man, but I have been a women's fat
loss-
Not the best look
Only audio in one ear.
Intermittent fasting.
That's a three out of 10.
Low carb diets or keto.
One out of 10.
Let's have a look for an outlier.
You want to lose weight
and eat fast food for breakfast?
This-
So you see how this video has done like
three times the numbers of everything
else.
I would have doubled down on this.
I'd do one for KFC.
I'd do one for Burger King.
I'd do one for McDonald's.
I'd do one for all of them because it
works.
Some kind of familiar brand
that you put into your hook worked,
so we need to
replicate that. Oh, and this one.
If you're a busy woman over 30
and you're struggling with the yo-yo diet
and your
motive-
So when you said if you're a busy woman
over 30, again, we saw an outlier, so we
should go with that.
I would pick the exact same backdrop.
I'd pick the exact same lighting.
I would just drop the football shirt.
Most women loathe football fans because
when they see that,
they just think of someone being like,
"United! United!
Forever blowing bubbles!
Bubbles!" So yeah.
And again,
just don't wear your sporting jerseys in
content
because you're getting political.
You're getting political.
You might think this is fine,
but you might as well just wear a MAGA
hat.
Stop eating pasta. Pasta, in no way,
is healthy.
Only got audio in one ear here again.
Stop eating pasta. Pasta-
So your audio's coming through, too.
Just check out your mono versus stereo
settings, and if you are
only getting unilateral audio from that,
you can duplicate
it in things like Premiere Pro in the
edit.
There seems to be no real
structure behind the content.
Seems to be a little bit all over the
place.
But what I would say is this:
for someone who's done 1,200 posts,
I would like to
have seen that you would get a hold of
what is working for you and you double
down on it.
It just seems a little bit late in the
process to still be trying to
find out what videos bang. There
are some outliers here
that just aren't getting
replicated.
That'd be my first point of call for you.
Now, who is this accountant?
Some of you here might have seen this guy
called Josh
Thomas Accountant,
and he would've been on your social media
talking about
accounting and whatnot.
And what's great is
if you look through his reels, you can
see that he consistently hits his reels in
the tens of thousands, and it's great.
Some of them do better.
Almost every single reel,
whatever he puts out, he's going
to hit over 10,000. Now, this
is going to take a minute,
but we'll do it anyway.
So everyone just sees this guy filming on
an expensive camera, all of his
videos. Look at this one, 923,000.
This guy's just a content expert, right?
This guy's just a G.
Then we go back, and you can tell
that there's a different backdrop here.
Throughout all of these stages,
he's just trying different things,
and he's obviously found a content bucket
that works, and he's grown his brand out
of it. So this backdrop, this edit,
this lighting, the three-piece, or
technically just the waist jacket
or whatever.
He would've also noticed, I guarantee it,
that when he wore that jacket with that
shirt, he got more views,
so that's all he wears.
Because here,
I guarantee whenever he wore the black
shirt, he didn't get the
same amounts, so he doubles down on that.
Just little things.
Again, he used to have the jacket on,
but then there's some point where he took
the
jacket off. Look at this.
I can actually see this. This
is interesting.
2,480, 66, 1.4 million. He knows that
he looks more legitimate
and the audience will think he's more
believable wearing the shirt with the
jacket, or whatever you call that,
than this.
Because here,
he does look a little bit like your cousin
that's come to your
wedding,
but here he looks like the bee's knees.
So then after this point,
he's just doubled down on that outfit,
but we keep going
back.
Now we hit a point where he used to just
wear a blue shirt, and he didn't
wear a tie, and his buttons are undone.
But here he's only 2,000, 2,000, 2,000,
3,000,
3,000, 3,000.
Then we go back even further.
The guy's making reels in his kitchen,
and then we go back to his first video.
If you're a limited company director
and you-
And this is filmed on not a professional
camera.
I think this is filmed on what?
Maybe an iPhone, maybe even a webcam.
Over time, he tries different things,
and you can just see the journey.
The first time he puts a fucking tie on.
Hey, what's happening everyone?
It's Josh at Thomas-
Only audio in one ear, but still, this
is the first time he would've bought the
road mic and not had the mono
or the stereo settings right.
Then he tries this one. Again,
for this one,
there's too much dead space up top.
Then he goes to a professional setup.
But he keeps pumping the same style,
the same topics, the
same things that people want to know.
Then over time,
he just improves marginally,
and you can see this arc of
him getting better and better
and better and better
and better over time.
And you can see him doubling into what
works, and then before you know it, you've
got nearly 100,000 followers as an
accountant.
So the reason I'm saying this
is I don't see this with your content.
We don't have that same arc, and there
is no process of
learning and adapting and getting better.
It's just too sporadic.
I need you to double down on some kind of
niche, some kind of setup, and resonate
because whenever you get an outlier,
you just don't seem to replicate them.
Now I want to get to your landing page.
This is what we call above the fold,
right?
This bit here. I'd love to see a VSL.
Love to have a video of you tell us about
this.
This stuff, meet the team, how it works,
resources, calculator,
blog, apply now. Apply.
I just don't like apply.
Typeform. Ugh. How much is it?
That's what I want to know.
How much is it?
Why will you fitness coaches never tell us
how much it
is?
Would you go to a restaurant where you
didn't know how much it is?
Would you fuck?
Would you stay in a hotel
that you didn't know how much it is?
Would you fuck? That's a stock image.
Don't like that.
Why are you not on your own landing page,
brother?
Why are you not here representing your
business?
Won't even tell me how much it is.
Hate that. This above the fold,
this area up here needs to be way better.
I need you.
I need a video explaining what it is.
I'd love to see the price.
What it is. Cool. What you get.
Would like that. It's all right.
This is a website, not a landing page.
I will die on this hill.
And to our final contender today,
Ben Radley Wedding Films.
Now, this is difficult because you
are doing a fantastic job at showcasing
your
work. [upbeat music] Lovely.
Content like this is great because it
shows people.
People go, "Oh, I want that at my wedding.
I want this guy.
I want to be those people." In every
story, the
protagonist is almost you seeing yourself
in that person, so I do
love the fact that people could watch this
and be like, "Wow, that could be me."
See, love seeing these shots. But there
is a problem, and that problem is
people don't care about other people,
right?
So if you were to say, "Oh,
this guy won the lottery." Don't care.
If it's my mate, I care because I go,
"Where are we going on holiday,
brother?" But
when it's someone else getting married,
people don't really care.
You know what I mean?
So it makes it difficult to showcase your
work because
they're like, "Yeah, I'm sure it
was a beautiful day, but I don't know you.
I don't know you, brother." If I
was to say, "There
was a terrible wedding that
happened yesterday with someone you didn't
know." You'd go, "I don't care.
I don't care." Do you know what I'm going
to say? There'll be a trial.
I could be wrong. What do I know?
I'm just a PT, but I could be wrong.
Salisbury.
I know Salisbury.
Used to play rugby against them.
I would love to see some videos of you
breaking down dos
and don'ts of wedding photography,
or dos and don'ts of weddings.
There are so many pieces of footage online
of people not getting the camera
settings right. Some people
are fucking up.
I would love for you to almost empower
and educate people about what
they must consider when having a wedding.
So, for instance, I'm just making this up.
Would you have a photographer
and a videographer at your wedding?
If so, tell me about that,
because the best cameras for video aren't
always the
best cameras for photos,
and you can't take photos
and record videos at the same
time. So you could even have a video
that goes, "If you're planning a wedding,
it's
important you know this." Well, actually,
no, that's not very good.
"A wedding videographer
is not enough on your special day.
You also need a photographer.
Most people make the mistake of thinking
they just
can have one person for the job.
But here's the issue.
A camera cannot record
and take photos at the same time.
So you either have amazing videos with bad
pictures, or you have pictures with no
videos. It's imperative
that you actually have two people with two
different
objectives using two different focal
lengths, and anyone that says that they
can do both with one camera
is going to miss moments from your special
day." Then
you could do another video going,
"Do you need to have a drone at your
wedding
getting shots? Well,
here's a wedding with,
here's a wedding without." So your page
could suddenly actually be empowering
wedding parties around the world to ensure
that they take the right proactive
measures to ensure they capture everything
on
their special day. But by doing so,
you are elevating your brand, your
persona, and getting clout
and status from it.
So there is some work you could do there
to just be like, "This is imperative.
You need this. Do we have static cameras?
Do we have moving cameras?
How many angles do you need?
How many people do you need there on the
day?" All
these kinds of things could really help
establish yourself as an authority.
And if you were to do that, if you
were to be out there as the number one
wedding
photographer expert in the whole of UK,
people will want to book you and
eventually your team for their weddings.
That's my gut instinct.
I like the page. I like this. Emotive,
unique, creative wedding films.
Do you know what I'd say here? Again,
I'm not a massive fan of text over video,
but
that looks all right.
Maybe even putting in a negative,
something cheesy like,
"You only have the best day of your life
once. Don't miss any moments." Oh.
[claps] "You only have the best day of
your life once.
Don't miss any moments." Because then
if they do get married again, you can say,
"Yeah, second marriage. Yeah,
that weren't the best day of your life
because you're
getting married again." Learn more.
Where's it going to take me?
Click here to watch some films.
Inquire here. It's all right. But this
is fine.
This is fine. I'll take this.
That's all right. Packages.
Do you know what?
I like this, brother. I like this.
You're telling me what I get
and how much it
costs. I thought there
was going to be a part of you then being a
weasel, hiding
the prices. But you know what? Mini film,
2 grand. Highlight film, 2.5 grand.
Short film, 3 grand. Is that it? Is
that it?
Bro, your work looks exceptional.
And do you know what?
I want to get you so much busier by doing
the social strategy we had before.
I'd like to see these numbers be 10X.
People go, "You spent 20 grand.
20 grand on a wedding videographer.
Why'd you spend that much?" Because he's
the best. All right.
Have you not seen his Instagram?
All right.
There's some insight to how I would do
some of those edits.
If you want me to do this to your page,
check out the link in the description